okay
and probably the most popularized
this of course is because of the work of
these guys
and
his discovery of the 19th quote close in
the Quran
he continues to do new work with the
computers
by means to the computer
I mean some other people here in the in
the basket or often started to get
involved
sister Iman has been doing a index of
the English translations
it's really taking a try to undertaking
for yourself
very important
you know these guys asked me to give
this food by the way because itself in
front of your shoes here had been doing
some work over at the University
of these last three to four months
and what we've been doing and putting
your Quran onto their computer onto the
computer over there
in order to reproduce the
workers have done
yeah
rather to shoot as many as you know is
assistance engineering student and it's
very knowledgeable about the continues
of what you can do with them my my role
in the project is when to type the
therapy Quran onto the computer itself
these guys complete but wanted me to say
a little bit about what we were doing
and why
um
as he starts and Dr mahul has repeated
many times here and he married code
many times and show us some of this
stuff
and also Dr mahu is additionally been
able to show us the connections between
the code and the actual value the letter
count value of many of you have
beautiful names of God
now when brother machine the night
started this project we'd have several
ideas in mind foreign
basket
um
is once we have an accurate file of the
quranic test on the community
in addition to reproducing
the work of documentary which is very
important to be confirming anything
scientifically
so this is an important value of doing
this kind of work
we will be able to do we'll also be able
to use the file that's create another
test too
the proud of them
or the statistical analysis any type of
project to the first place
in investigating some of the other
possible relationships
um
we hope for the last one day
when this works is completed this mosque
here in addition to having the Quran and
the various books of documentary
available for distribution but we will
also be able to have computer tapes or
disks available
that other people can can check out Dr
Khalifa's work or do other
investigations on their own or verify it
against judicial effects without having
to go through all the things
now
the machine is passed out here with some
printouts and this is some of our
initial work we've just really done only
five
five tours again
and these are printouts with the results
from two or 42 and silver 50.
showing not only the count of the car
which is which is
42x67 costs
this
so this is
and the initial example
of being able to reproduce yourself
so
I got most of the cutback today I want
to talk more family
because we don't really have any new
resources more of the experience that
we've had and some of the bases for this
kind of breathing faces for
the importance of the computer in
relation to the Quran itself
now as many of you know who spent any
time at all
even a profit calculator
working with the computer
changes our habits of thinking
the way we perceive the world around is
particularly mathematically and in terms
of the logic to the use
the effect of computers in every aspect
of their life seems to have become even
more overwhelming in the last few years
well they've got to stop and remember
that God knew all about computers
even before the beginning of the world
though he only released this knowledge
to us living in the last part of the
20th century
there's a potential benefits we may get
using Computing computers also makes us
vulnerable to potential Mysteries
indeed God's gift to the communities
other computers places a heavy burden of
responsibility on us to use it for being
here
and when we witnessed today that the
majority of people are overwhelmed or
impressed by the powers
and many people are afraid of confused
many people seem to think
they're almost god-like
the stuff
we must always remember the community
the computer is really no more than a
piece of iron
and we can look to Surah 57
and the famous curse there verse 25
tells us we have sent our messages with
clear Revelations and we will accept
them the scripture and law to spread
justice among the people we also sent
down iron wherein there is great force
and power as well as benefits for the
people
this that God May distinguish
those who support him and his Messengers
and good things God is most powerful
Almighty now we can take firing this
sword to refer not just to the smelting
the particular metal into all kinds of
technology and certainly it's a
potentials of the computer both to
benefit the harm
moving deep computers are one of God's
Supreme and giving blessed giving
blessings
to the human being
to be used or misused according to what
is in the hearts of people
now
God ordained that the computer would be
the final scripture he would give us
and because his plan was the 14th
centuries later
he was going to allow the people to
discover how to make and use computers
the computer would open up increasing
knowledge of the marbles of God's
creation let the people see and talk to
each other all over the planet planet
via the satellite
or go to the Moon or learn more about
the inner inner Mysteries of the Genies
and the atoms all of these are only
possible for us to do because of the
computers the computer also allows us to
wage nuclear warfare
now we know all this new knowledge we
overwhelm the people
you know God knew that all this new
knowledge would overwhelm the people and
even make people suppose that they have
discovered the computer independently of
God's Will and even forget God entirely
God wanted to reassure the Believers who
would be living in such a fantastically
a new world is opened by the computer
as we and as we're seeing unveiled to us
all around every day
God wanted to let us know living with us
people who are living in the age of
computers to clearly know that he fully
controls the computers along with the
rest of the situation
will handle it
verse six of six zero six verse 101
tells us God is the designer of the
Heaven and Earth and he created all
things and he was fully aware of all
things
Surah 18 verse 7 he created everything
on Earth as a dormant in order to test
him there with and distinguish the good
dealers this is exactly what 057 told us
about the purpose of iron and Technology
and God put a codedness message in the
Quran in his final scripture that could
be found and appreciated only after the
computers
in this way God not only proved us that
he has preserved the written Integrity
of the Quran every word every letter
as has been discussed here many times
he proves to us that he controls the
computer which was needed to make this
discovery
now we should appreciate
the exact timing by which the computer
message was delivered
I mean if we look back at just the
recent history of the computer itself in
the 1940s and 1950s the modern computer
was just being developed
and it was going from having some
mechanical gears to off the electronics
first using the big old vacuum tubes and
finally transistors
now these were called first and second
generation computers and only a few
hundred or a few thousand
could be made they were very expensive
and they needed to room the size of a
gymnasium to housing
then in the mid 1950s and early 60s
miniature circuits and microchips began
to be divorced
these became the third generation
computers now these are the large ones
that are used by universities and
businesses and they process information
thousands of times faster than the
original computers
this is the kind of computer that ustaz
collection was using when he first
discovered the miracle in the Quran
it's the kind of computer they have over
here at the University Computer Center
but the little pqs the ones you see back
in office ones you see advertised on TV
or one of your magazines
the computer science is called a fourth
generation of computers and they
represent the real computer Revolution
they're only been commercially available
the last three or four years and only in
the last year or so it prices that very
many people could afford
some now are only a hundred to three or
four hundred dollars and you just took
them out to the TV show
now we can notice that this timing
coincides with the publication of this
size is translational of the Quran and
the
proliferation of the information about
the 19 code in the Quran itself
the his book the computer speaks in his
other words
now the mathematical Miracle of the
Quran of course isn't
only to be studied and appreciated by
people who have access to Big computers
in universities or IBM or such places
it's to be appreciated by everyone
and
and though we don't need a computer
to appreciate the Miracles occur on
itself with or without knowledge of the
code
the fact is that the computer is
affecting so many people's lives
and so the appreciation of the code to
the computers very important I think
since God exactly timed the release of
the computer miracle in the Quran he
also plan
the exact timing of the release of these
many computers and availability to
everyone
he planned the beginning of the 1980s
the computer was going to start becoming
as common as TVs and radios and cars
I was hearing on the radio the other day
about how some illegal manufacturers
over in Hong Kong and Singapore were
illegally making many computers
and putting famous names on them for
black market sales
in Asia and Africa and the Middle East
at one half to one-third the price of
the real thing
you know we can't approve of such
practices
but it is a good illustration
of just how proliferated the many
computers become
and it shows that many computers are not
just in big demand not just in the U.S
and Japan Europe
but all over the world even the poorest
countries
so we can take it as a sign to
appreciate even more how major a change
the computer was making the lives of all
the people in the world
not just us in what we've probably
developed
and we can further recognize how God
controls to continue and why it is so
important to put a commute a
computerized message in the Quran when
he put it in Muhammad's heart
verse 102 of Surah 6 says such is God's
delivered there is no God except he the
creator of all things therefore you
shall worship him alone he is in full
control of all things
therefore let us turn to God and ask him
for guidance and forgiveness
in the second part in the second part of
my foot by today I want to talk a little
bit about my personal experience while I
was working on this computer typing in
the stores
not only did it make me appreciate the
enormity of the task that Dr Khalifa did
over the years that he worked
computer miracle
and especially since when he started out
he had no idea what he was looking for
it also makes me really appreciate
how impossible it would be for
someone to deliberately put this 19th
over
Quran
to human design
especially people who didn't even have
computers to keep track
of all the words and letters and where
they placed everything
now I had an Arabic class over the
university and I just one year and
taught me how to read the alphabet and
taught me a little vocabulary and some
basic grammar
but unlike Dr Khalifa
I don't really understand the Arabic so
when I'm typing it's basically all I'm
doing is typing in letters
um
sometimes I'm not even sure where a word
but
as I've been typing it I do read the
Arabic cancer
and
I get used to words and patterns and I
compare it with the English text which
is wearing my core on the side so I am
learning more vocabulary
and
it's really
even with only partly understanding
Arabic sometimes I really get choked up
just from the senseless
kind of jump at me and I'll start
wondering what's being said here and
then I'll go and look at it
and it's kind of a strange experience
um
but even without understanding the
actual meanings of meaning rewards I
became to recognize me and just because
they are repeated over and over and as I
type I was constantly struck by the odd
Sensations for patterns and things going
on that I really can't articulate
it seemed to me not only
are their rhythms and when we hear the
Quran inside it
but there are patterns in the letters
themselves
and because of this experience I'm more
convinced not only that the choices of
words and spelling in the Quran are
designed to accommodate the 19 codes
but every word and every letter is
chosen placed exactly for specific
purpose
now when I read the Quran I'm reminded
of
patterns and rules of logic which I
learned in computer programs
well I can't offer you any specific
evidence
for this statement
I will only offer you some of the
thoughts that I've had
the
leads me to make this kind of statement
um
you know we're all aware of the Quran
is written in an unusual style unlike
any other book
it's almost the first thing that
everyone knows when they're reading the
Quran for the first time we find a few
verses talking about one subject and
then suddenly the next person to be
talking about some entirely different
session we find ourselves jumping to
verses and other sewers scattered all
over the Quran to continue learning
additional information on the Pacific
subject
and this is not the style of an ordinary
book of literature philosophy and poetry
where the writer keeps his subject
development following a linear sequence
of logic
it is very much the style of a complex
computer program
which sends the computer jumping around
to different sets of instructions and
other parts of the programs and Back
Again
in order for the computer to keep track
of where it should go for the next step
the program uses numbers and specific
names as addresses so the computer will
not get lost
now when we're reading the Quran we
sometimes find the same verse numbers
and different surahs are talking about
the same stuff
and it reminds me of this aspect of the
computer program
but I must remind you that this is only
a speculation and there's I have no
consistent role to offer you
so I only submit to you is a further
area for possibly investigation
and another character
of the Arabic Quran is Christine
comparing it with the rules of computer
programming is a very specific use of
words
in our quranic studies the stars believe
that Dr mahore
have
often Divine Attention our attention to
the precise use of words and verses we
are discussing and comparing them to the
same usages and restatements of points
and verses elsewhere
now in computer programming we want to
communicate to the computer specific
instruction or piece of information it
is absolutely essential that we use
precise words
anytime that same instruction or piece
of data is repeated we must use the same
precise words
it's called the address
if we don't the computer doesn't know
what we're talking about for example
the electric company might use a
computer card
with a bunch of holes in it to process
our electric field
now one set of holes in that computer
card
tells the computer the customer number
and then every customer has a different
number
so the program has to tell the computer
that is still talking about the same
thing
and it caused that set of holes wherever
the number is
as a customer number
when we find something similar in the
Quran
when we take the word for example Isle
which can be translated is sign Miracle
moral verse and revelation
and
and various other translations that you
see in the different translations to it
uh
it's translated by these various uh
words depending on the context in which
it is used
and even though there are other possible
words in the Arab group it could be used
the Quran always sticks with the word
Iowa
so yes is consistent
whether the eyes we're talking about is
the party in the sea for Moses to the
the creation
the pattern of the uh the Sun and the
Moon around each other
the signs that they will show to that
Moses
the letters in the source are called
Ayah the the verses that were sent down
were called ayat
um descending of the Ring to go to clock
now
there's many many examples
now they're all named Aya
so that we can understand that all these
different signs and miracles are for one
purpose
their proof of God's power over
everything
two or six verse 105 thus do we bury the
signs the eye to let them realize
that you have learned and we explain the
signs to the people who have knowledge
well I hope they haven't been too long
certainly my own experience in working
with a computer makes me appreciate
even more the Miracles
and how complex and difficult Dr Keith
his own work was
and really
you couldn't have discovered it by
intention
and it makes me appreciate even more
just how extraordinary and exhaustive
the Quran itself is
it becomes really attempting to go far
afield and exploring the technical
structures across
how many letters and words there are in
the choice of words the arrangement of
verses and sewers and much much more
but really the important thing in the
end is what was important in the first
place is to believe in worship God
and we should strive to understand
what the words of the Quran say telling
us how to worship God
and how the leadership
all this elaboration and mathematical
detail May occupy our minds like a great
puzzle but this is the nature of our
minds of the way God designed it
still in the end what we are learning
is nothing more than we bore witness to
and a creation
there is no God to God
so let us worship God alone and work
righteousness
thank you
Allah
this is
[Music]
number
one
[Music]
this is
foreign
for example
[Music]